Seppo Enarvi

CONTACT INFORMATION Aalto University

School of Electrical Engineering

Department of Signal Processing

and Acoustics Otakaari 3 FI-02150 Espoo

Finland

GENERAL Interests All aspects of machine learning, especially deep learning. My postgraduate research has involved speech recognition and language modeling, but I have a lot of interest in computer vision as well. I have a strong background in software development and enjoy designing new algorithms. I want to to learn constantly and stay on top of this fast changing field.

Mobile: +358-44-322-5563

E-mail: seppo2017@marjaniemi.com

WWW: http://senarvi.github.io/

EDUCATION

Aalto University School of Electrical Engineering,

Department of Signal Processing and Acoustics,

Espoo, Finland

Doctor of Science (Technology)

July 2017 (Expected)

- Research Field: Automatic Speech Recognition
- Thesis: Modeling conversational Finnish for automatic speech recognition

Aalto University School of Science,

Department of Information and Computer Science,

Espoo, Finland

Licentiate of Science (Technology)

September 2007 to September 2012

- Research Field: Computer and Information Science
- Thesis: Finnish language speech recognition for dental health care

Helsinki University of Technology,

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Espoo, Finland

Master of Science (Technology)

September 1999 to August 2006

- Major: Interactive Digital Media
- Minor: Telecommunications Software
- Extended curriculum in mathematics and physics
- Thesis: Image-based detection of defective logs

RESEARCH AND TRAINING

International Computer Science Institute,

Berkeley, USA

Visiting Researcher

February 2012 to August 2012

• Worked on speech recognition for conversational speech.

Asian Institute of Technology School of Engineering and Technology,

Information and Communications Group,

Pathumthani, Thailand

Exchange Student

August 2005 to December 2005

The Finnish Defence Forces.

Guard Jaeger Regiment

Military Service

January 2000 to December 2000

 \bullet Rank: Corporal

WORK HISTORY

Aalto University,

Espoo, Finland

Doctoral Candidate

January 2011 to present

- Worked on subword, class, and neural network language models.
- Developed AaltoASR decoder and server backend (C++).
- Developed TheanoLM language modeling toolkit (Python).
- Collected a conversational Finnish text corpus from the Internet using data selection algorithms.
- Supervised collection of an acoustic training corpus (DSPCON).

Genera Oy, Helsinki, Finland

Software Designer

May 2001 to December 2011

- Implemented new graphical features to display panel software (C++).
- Designed and developed a distributed system for updating content to KONE InfoScreen elevator displays (C++, PHP, JavaScript).
- Developed image analysis algorithms and designed computer vision systems for timber grading and internal quality control (C++).
- Developed Mitla software for timber measurement and refining (Visual Basic).
- Developed configuration script parsers for control and diagnostics panels (Perl).

JOKO Executive Education Oy, Helsinki, Finland

Computer Assistant

April 1999 to May 1999 June 1998 to July 1998

- Performed local area network administration.
- Produced graphic content for course material.
- Provided assistance with office software, desktop computers, and A/V equipment.

City of Helsinki Education Department, Helsinki, Finland

IT Project Tutor

January 1998 to May 1998

- Teached common desktop software to school teachers.
- Scanned photographs for Picture Archives of Helsinki City Museum.

PUBLICATIONS

Seppo Enarvi, Mikko Kurimo (2016)

TheanoLM – An Extensible Toolkit for Neural Network Language Modeling In Proceedings of the 17th Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association (INTERSPEECH)

Mikko Kurimo, Seppo Enarvi, Ottokar Tilk, Matti Varjokallio, André Mansikkaniemi, and Tanel Alumäe (2016)

Modeling under-resourced languages for speech recognition Language Resources and Evaluation (LRE)

Seppo Enarvi and Mikko Kurimo (2013)

Studies on Training Text Selection for Conversational Finnish Language Modeling In Proceedings of the 10th International Workshop on Spoken Language Translation (IWSLT 2013)

Seppo Enarvi and Mikko Kurimo (2013)

A Novel Discriminative Method for Pruning Pronunciation Dictionary Entries In Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Speech Technology and Human-Computer Dialogue (SpeD 2013) Programming Expertise I am especially confident in C++ and Python. I've used the Standard Template Library, Boost C++ Libraries, NumPy, and Theano extensively. Other programming languages I have used in the past include Java, PHP, Perl, and assembly languages. I have experience in concurrent programming and network programming, and I am keen to write aesthetic, maintainable code.

Spoken

Finnish (native), English (excellent written and spoken), Swedish (fluent written and fair spoken), German (fair written)

OPEN-SOURCE SOFTWARE

Languages

Author of TheanoLM, an open source toolkit for language modeling using neural networks. Contributed to AaltoASR, Aalto University speech recognizer.

LAST UPDATED May 4th, 2017